## BEATRICE NYAWA CHILONGA

Phone Number : +260966349796

Email: beatrice.chilonga@aims-

cameroon.org

AIMS Cameroon
P.O Box 608
Crystal Cardon Lin

Crystal Garden, Limbe

Cameroon.

#### **OBJECTIVE**

I am an enthusiastic, innovative and practical Mathematician, hard-working and determined. I am committed to analyzing and evaluating problems, conducting extensive researches and constantly enhancing my abilities. I am motivated to learn, grow, excel and inspire on a daily basis.

#### **EDUCATION**

### African Institute for Mathematical Sciences, Limbe, Cameroon .

August 2023

MSc in Mathematical Sciences
 Expected graduation date June 2024

## **Evelyn Hone College of Applied Arts and Commerce, Lusaka, Zambia.**

 Certificate in Project Management, Monitoring and Evaluation (April 2023 – May 2023)

## Copperbelt University, Kitwe, Zambia.

 BSc in Mathematics (2017 - 2021)

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Levy Mwanawasa Medical University, Zambia Mathematics Tutor (Part time)

April 2022 – August 2023

- Provide group tutoring to students
- Solve and analyze tutorial sheets
- Provide students with positive and constructive feedback
- Grade tests and quizzes
- Provide guidance and mentorship to those lagging behind, experiencing difficulties
- Meet students clarify and review concepts taught in class

# Copperbelt University, Zambia Mathematics Tutor (Part time)

May 2021 – June 2021

• Instill confidence in students, provide face to face mathematical lessons

Address

- Be an active listener committed to helping students overcome academic challenges to reach personal goals
- Empower students with constructive feedback and practical test-taking strategies

#### **SKILLS**

- Excellent time management
- Quick leaner
- Critical thinking
- Proficient at multi-tasking.
- Fluent in English and basic in French
- Intermediate with Python, LaTeX and beginner in SageMath
- Project management, monitoring and evaluation
- Effective communication and analytical skills

### **REFERENCES**

Name : Paul A Taylor, PhD Position : Core Director

Institution: Scientific and Statistical Computing Core, NIMH, NIH, USA

Email: paul.taylor@nih.gov, pault@aims.ac.za

Phone: +1 301 402 1352

Name : James Muchinga

Position : Lecturer

Institution: Levy Mwanawasa Medical University, Lusaka, Zambia

Email : <u>jamesm@aims.ac.za</u> Phone : +260 96 9982987

Name :Eddy Kwessi Position : Professor

Institution: Trinity University, USA

Email: ekwessi@trinity.edu

Address: 1 Trinity Pl, San Antonio, TX 78212